MOHAMAD ZAMINI

Laramie, WY 82070 7012157110 mohamad.zamini@gmail.com

WWW: Web

SI	M	Л	A	R	V	7

As a PhD student in Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing, I specialize in visual and text reasoning. I also excel in deploying large language models (LLMs) effectively. My solid foundation in software engineering has empowered me to make meaningful contributions to notable projects such as **Pytorch-Geometric**, **LangChain**, **Open-Assistant**, **Gymnasium**, **and Gorilla**. I excel in collaborative teams and driving projects to success.

EXPERIENCE

NUMENTA

Redwood City, CA

Machine Learning Intern

07/2024 to 11/2024

- Fine-tuned LLM models, including Mistral, LLaMA, and GPT, leveraging techniques such as activation sparsity and attention sparsity to optimize performance.
- Developed techniques such as KWTA, dynamic context pruning, and KV caching.

PETROLERN

Atlanta, GA

Digital Innovation Intern

06/2022 to 08/2024

- During my internship at Petrolern as a Digital Innovation Intern, I gained experience in both machine learning and data compression techniques
- I developed a semantic compression technique using a deep autoencoder to effectively map data tuples into a lower-dimensional representation
- As a machine learning engineer, I built models for analyzing geothermal data and improved their performance through algorithmic optimization

LIFEWEB

Tehran, Iran

NLP Engineer

06/2018 to 08/2019

- Fine-tune models like BART for summarization on Persian text data.
- Implementing Matrix Factorization for topic modeling.
- BiLSTM-CRF Models for sequential tagging.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

PH.D.: COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Wyoming, Laramie, WY

Area of research: Causal Reasoning for Improving Generalization in Visual Question Answering

- Generated new benchmark dataset.
- Developed interpretable Visual Question Answering (VQA) models for the Benchmark dataset.
- Utilized LLMs to generate causal explanations for answers.
- Currently working on applying diffusion models to accurately decompose occluded shapes within our dataset, leveraging their capacity to model intricate data distributions and reveal obscured details.

MASTER OF SCIENCE: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

09/2018

University of Tarbiat Modares, Tehran, Iran

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER ENGINEERING

09/2016

University of Science And Culture, Tehran, Iran

PAPERS

- Zamini, M., Shukla, D. (AAAI 25 Submission). Q-Route: Quaternion based Actor-Critic for KG Reasoning
- Zamini, M., Reza, H. & Rabiei, M. (2022). A review of knowledge graph completion. Information, 13(8), 396.
- Zamini, M., Montazer, G. Credit card fraud detection using autoencoder based clustering. In 2018 9th International Symposium on Telecommunications (IST), 486-491. IEEE.

Machine Learning PyTorch Python Programming Data Visualization PyTorch Codebase Distributed programming

TEACHING ASSISTANT EXPERIENCES

- Introduction to Programming
- Introduction to Artificial intelligence
- Software Design